Harold H. Burton Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Supreme Court File, 1792-1965 (Box 56-325)
  - Miscellany, 1792-1964 (Box 308-325)
    Printed and bound opinions, statements from the bench, notes, lists, Court budgets and statistics, hearing lists, case assignments, notes and memoranda from other justices, correspondence, reports, and newsletters.
    Arranged alphabetically by type of material, topic, or name of organization and chronologically therein.
    - Appointment calendars, 1953-1960 (Box 308)
    - Case assignments, 1947-1950 (Box 309)
    - Court budgets
      - 1945-1951 See also Oversize, (13 folders)
      - 1952-1956, (12 folders) (Box 310)
      - 1957-1958, (12 folders) (Box 311)
      - 1959, (3 folders) (Box 312)
    - Court statistics
      - October terms
        - 1944-1958, (15 folders)
        - 1959-1963, (5 folders) (Box 313)
    - Disposition of argued cases, proposed improvements, 1950-1951
    - The Docket Sheet (newsletter), 1959-1964, (5 folders)
    - Hearing lists, 1954-1963
    - Inventory of records in the Supreme Court building, 1959
    - Keogh jurisdiction bill, notes by Felix Frankfurter, 1945-1946, (2 folders)
    - Labor-Management Relations Act of 1947, section 301, 1955-1957, (2 folders)
    - Memoranda and notes from other justices, 1945-1959, (10 folders) (Box 314)
    - Moot court competition
      - 1948-1951, (6 folders)
      - 1952-1959, (14 folders) (Box 315)
    - Notes (Box 316)
      - Lower federal court cases, undated, (3 folders)
      - Miscellaneous, 1945-1962, (3 folders)
      - Supreme Court history, 1792, undated, (9 folders); (7 folders) (Box 317)
    - Opinions by Burton (printed copies)
      - Set I
        - October terms
          - 1945-1946, (4 folders)
          - 1947-1949, (12 folders) (Box 318)
          - 1950-1953, (13 folders) (Box 319)
          - 1954-1957, (13 folders) (Box 320)
      - Set II (Box 321)
        - October terms
          - 1945-1950, (2 vols.)
          - 1951-1954 (Box 322)
    - Order lists
      - October terms
        - 1962, (4 folders)
        - 1963, (4 folders) (Box 323)
    - Rules
      - Admiralty rules, 1953
      - Federal rules of civil procedure, 1950-1962, undated
      - Federal rules of criminal procedure, 1947, 1954-1956, undated
      - Supreme Court rules, 1948-1957, undated, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 324)
    - Statements from the bench by Burton
      - October terms
        - 1945-1954, (10 folders)
        - 1955-1957, (3 folders) (Box 325)
    - United States Court of Appeals for the Second Circuit, 1955
    - United States Court of Appeals for the Third Circuit, 1944-1954, undated, (3 folders)
    - United States courts of appeals and state courts, announcement of written opinions, 1952 See also Oversize
    - Visitors to the Court, statistics, 1956-1964, (2 folders)
- United States Court of Appeals File, 1958-1962 (Box 325-342)
  Printed, typed, and handwritten copies of opinions, circulated opinions, notes, briefs, memoranda, reports, and transcripts.
  Grouped chronologically by the court's annual September terms with individual cases arranged numerically by docket number therein.
  - Case file (Box 325)
    - September term 1958
      - Lists of cases and notes
      - Frontier Broadcasting Co. v. United States, 14,395; (2 folders)
      - Seigel v.Watson, 14,417; (2 folders) (Box 326)
      - Frontier Broadcasting Co. v. Federal Communications Comm'n See Container 325, 14,395, 14,539
      - Bakersfield Broadcasting Co. v. United States, 14,541
      - Day v. Providence Hosp., 14,564; (3 folders)
      - Day v. Dani See same container, 14,564, 14,565
      - Tag v. Rogers, 14,591; (2 folders) (Box 327)
      - Royall v. Yudelevit, 14,608
      - Barger v. Mumford, 14,653; (3 folders)
      - Lohr v. Bishop, 14,673
      - McNamara v. Riggs National Bank of Washington, D.C., 14,676; (2 folders)
      - Central States Drivers Council v. National Labor Relations Bd., 14,726; (2 folders) (Box 328)
      - Peltier v. Seaton, 14,744; (2 folders)
      - Borges v. United States, 14,746; (2 folders)
      - Griffin v. United States, 14,766
      - Lockley v. United States, 14,775; (2 folders)
      - Anderson v. United States, 14,824
      - American Fidelity Co. v. National City Bank of Evansville, 14,831; (2 folders)
      - American Fidelity Co. v. National City Bank of Evansville See same container, 14,831, 14,832
      - Kelley v. Safeway Stores, 14,841; (3 folders) (Box 329)
      - Robbins v. Reed, 14,883
    - September term 1959
      - Lists of cases, memoranda, and notes, (2 folders)
      - Lord v. Lencshire House, Ltd., 14,886
      - Lencshire House, Ltd. v. Lord See same container, 14,886, 14,888
      - Red River Broadcasting Corp. v. Federal Communications Comm'n, 14,948; (2 folders)
      - Rogers v. Societé Internationale pour Participations Industrielles et Commerciales, 15,017
      - Berloff v. Whittier, 15,031
      - Rotan ex rel. Estate of Wade v. Greenbaum, 15,037 (Box 330)
      - International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union v. National Labor Relations Bd., 15,038; (3 folders)
      - Whittier v. Emmet, 15,066; (4 folders); (1 folder) (Box 331)
      - United States v. Deering See Container 330, 15,066, 15,067
      - United States v. Mabbutt See Container 330, 15,066, 15,068
      - National Labor Relations Bd. v. Bernhard-Altmann Tex. Corp. See Container 330, 15,038, 15,079
      - Bowdan v. Gooderham & Worts, Ltd., 15,157
      - Spann v. Richmond, Fredericksburg & Potomac R.R., 15,168
      - Dillard v. Dillard, 15,200; (3 folders)
      - Plains Television Corp. v. Federal Communications Comm'n, 15,204
      - Angland v. Doe, 15,206; (1 folder) (Box 332)
      - Dechter v. United States, 15,252
      - Frazier v. United States, 15,261; (2 folders)
      - Gravette v. United States See same container, 15,261, 15,267
      - Performed Line Prods. Co. v. Watson, 15,270
      - Street v. Federal Power Comm'n, 15,274; (2 folders)
      - Jackson v. United States, 15,292; (2 folders)
      - Johnson v. United States, 15,343 (Box 333)
      - McNeil v. Seaton, 15,351; (4 folders)
      - Porter v. Herter, 15,394
      - Moore v. United States, 15,405
      - Angland v. Doe See Container 331, 15,206, 15,413 (Box 334)
      - Bryant v. Mathis, 15,417
      - Snook v. Safeway Stores, 15,493
    - September term 1960
      - Lists of cases, memoranda, and notes
      - Great Lakes Broadcasting Co. v. Federal Communications Comm'n, 14,638; (3 folders)
      - Worthy v. Dulles, 14,806; (2 folders)
      - Arnold v. District of Columbia, 15,588
      - California v. Federal Power Comm'n, 15,687; (1 folder); (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 335, Box 336)
      - Barry v. United States, 15,763; (2 folders) (Box 337)
      - Barry v. United States See same container, 15,763, 15,765
      - District of Columbia v. Lewis, 15,780; (4 folders)
      - Campbell v. United States, 15,820; (4 folders)
      - Washington Housing Corp. v. Butts, 15,839
      - Springfield Airport Auth. v. Civil Aeronautics Bd., 15,853; (2 folders) (Box 338)
      - Goddard v. District of Columbia Redevelopment Land Agency, 15,868
      - Goddard v. United States See same container, 15,868, 15,869
      - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Co. v. Federal Trade Comm'n, 15,877; (2 folders)
      - Bigelow-Sanford Carpet Co. v. Federal Trade Comm'n See same container, 15,877, 15,894
      - Mile Branch Coal Co. v. United Mine Workers, 15,907; (2 folders)
      - Adelman v. St. Louis Fire & Marine Ins. Co., 15,916; (2 folders)
      - Shearer v. Bakery & Confectionery Workers' Int'l Union, 15,937
      - Hearst Consol. Publications v. American Newspaper Guild, 15,973 (Box 339)
      - Jordan v. United Ins. Co. of Am., 15,994; (2 folders)
      - Courtaulds, Inc. v. Kintner, 16,054; (2 folders)
      - White v. Clemmer, 16,143; (2 folders)
      - Childs v. Clemmer See same container, 16,143, 16,144
      - Yochelson v. McLaughlin, 16,217
    - September term 1961
      - Lists of cases and notes
      - Thompson v. Gleason, 16,014; (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 340)
      - Kidd v. Federal Communications Comm'n, 16,286; (3 folders)
      - Lewis v. Hogwood, 16,296; (2 folders)
      - Hepner v. Chozik, 16,318
      - Gager v. Seidel, 16,394; (3 folders)
      - Matthews v. Britton, 16,498; (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 341)
      - Roberts v. United States, 16,531
      - Walker v. United States, 16,663
      - De Binder v. United States, 16,846; (3 folders)
    - September term 1962
      - List of cases
      - Reisman v. Caplin, 16,690; (2 folders); (1 folder) (Box 342)
      - Stevan v. Union Trust Co. of the District of Columbia, 16,865; (3 folders)
- Speeches and Writings File, 1878-1962 (Box 342-372)
  Handwritten, typed, and printed copies of articles, speeches, statements, and radio broadcasts, a book, notes, printed matter, and research material.
  Organized alphabetically by articles, book, a chronological file, political speeches, radio broadcast file, and a subject file and arranged chronologically or alphabetically therein.
  - Articles about the Supreme Court (Box 342)
    - 1947
      - July, “The Supreme Court: Mr. Justice Burton Gives an Interesting Comparison,” American Bar Association Journal
      - Oct., “Judging Is Also Administration,” Temple Law Quarterly, (3 folders)
    - 1948
      - Dec., “Some of the Unsung Services of the Supreme Court of the United States,” Cleveland Bar Association Journal, (1 folder); (2 folders) (Box 343)
    - 1950
      - Jan., “The Continuity of the United States Supreme Court,” Journal of the National Association of Referees in Bankruptcy
      - Oct., “The Cornerstone of Constitutional Law: The Extraordinary Case of Marbury v. Madison,” American Bar Association Journal, (2 folders)
    - 1951
      - Oct., “Justice the Guardian of Liberty: John Marshall at the Trial of Aaron Burr,” American Bar Association Journal, (3 folders)
    - 1952
      - Dec., “The Dartmouth College Case: A Dramatization,” American Bar Association Journal, (1 folder); (3 folders) (Box 344)
    - 1953
      - Jan., “The Story of the Place,” George Washington Law Review, (3 folders)
      - Dec., “An Independent Judiciary: The Keystone of Our Freedom,” American Bar Association Journal, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 345)
    - 1955
      - Feb.,”Two Significant Decisions: Ex parte Milligan and Ex parte McCardle,” American Bar Association Journal, (5 folders)
      - Oct., “John Marshall - The Man,” University of Pennsylvania Law Review, (2 folders)
    - 1956 (Box 346)
      - Mar., “The Legal Tender Cases: A Celebrated Supreme Court Reversal,” American Bar Association Journal, (3 folders)
    - 1957
      - Feb., “The Independence and Continuity of the Supreme Court of the United States,” The Reporter (Phi Alpha Delta Law Fraternity)
  - Book, 600 Days' Service: A History of the 361st Infantry Regiment of the United States Army (Portland, Oreg.: James, Kerns & Abbott Co., 1921)
  - Chronological file
    - Set I
      - Index
      - 1927, June-1937, Sept., (3 folders)
      - 1937, Nov.-1940, Dec., (10 folders) (Box 347)
    - Set II
      - Index
      - 1941, Jan.-Mar.
      - 1941, Apr.-1944, Jan., (13 folders) (Box 348)
      - 1944, Feb.-1950, Oct., (13 folders) (Box 349)
      - 1950, Dec.-1952, Dec., (2 folders) (Box 350)
    - Set III
      - Index
      - 1953, Jan.-1962, Dec., (5 folders)
  - Political speeches, 1936-1940, (4 folders)
  - Radio broadcast file
    - Lists
    - 1935-1937, (2 folders)
    - 1938-1940, undated, (6 folders) (Box 351)
  - Subject file
    - African-Americans, 1939-1944, undated
    - Agriculture, 1941-1943
    - Alaska, 1942
    - “America Looks Ahead,” 1937-1944, undated, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 352)
    - American Legion, 1925-1941, undated, (7 folders)
    - American Palestine Committee, 1934-1941, undated
    - American Red Cross, 1934-1941, undated, (3 folders)
    - American unity, 1941 (Box 353)
    - Armed forces, United States
      - Army, 1933-1940, undated
      - Navy, 1937-1942, undated
    - Armistice Day, 1928-1941, undated
    - Art exhibits, 1940
    - Aviation and aircraft, 1929-1945, undated, (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 354)
    - “A” miscellaneous, 1935-1941, undated, (2 folders)
    - Baker, Newton D., 1926, 1938
    - Battle of Lake Erie (1813), 1937-1938
    - Beveridge, William, Sir, and the Beveridge Plan, 1943
    - Blossom, Dudley S., memorial, 1938-1939 (Box 355)
    - “The Boy and His Future” (radio program), 1933-1934
    - Buffalo, N.Y., dedication of Memorial Auditorium, 1937-1940
    - “B” miscellaneous, 1934-1958, undated, (2 folders)
    - Capitol Page School, Washington, D.C., 1952-1953
    - Christmas day greetings, 1938-1939
    - Christmas Seal program, 1937
    - Citizenship training, 1931-1941, undated, (3 folders)
    - Civic organizations and clubs, 1938-1942
    - Civil liberties, 1940
    - Cleveland, Ohio, 1931-1940, undated, (1 folder); (7 folders) (Box 356)
    - Cleveland Community Fund, Cleveland, Ohio, 1938-1941
    - Clum, Alfred, tribute, 1938
    - Commencement addresses
      - 1932-1938, (2 folders)
      - 1939-1945, undated, (3 folders) (Box 357)
    - Commerce, 1945
    - Communism, 1932-1942, undated
    - Congress, United States
      - Elections, 1942
      - Reorganization, 1942-1945
      - Wartime Congress, 1942-1943, undated
    - Conservation, 1931-1932, undated
    - Constitution, United States, 1934-1945, undated, (4 folders)
    - Crime prevention, 1930-1940, undated, (3 folders) (Box 358)
    - Cultural Gardens of Cleveland, Ohio, 1937-1940
    - “C-D” miscellaneous, 1928-1945, undated, (3 folders)
    - Economy, 1936-1941, undated, (2 folders)
    - Electoral College, 1944
    - Employment and manpower, 1945, (1 folder) (Box 359)
    - “E” miscellaneous, 1937-1943, undated, (2 folders)
    - Faith, 1943-1944
    - Fathers and sons, 1933-1944
    - Federal budget, 1934-1940
    - Federal government, 1940-1945
    - Foreign countries
      - China, 1932-1938, undated
      - Czechoslovakia, 1937-1939, undated, (2 folders)
      - Germany, 1934-1944, undated
      - Great Britain, 1934-1945, undated
      - Hungary, 1934-1944, undated
      - Italy, 1932-1938
      - Japan, 1944-1945
      - Lebanon, 1941-1944, undated
      - Lithuania, 1938, undated
      - Miscellany, 1939-1945, undated
      - Poland, 1943-1944, undated, (2 folders) (Box 360)
      - USSR, 1938-1945, undated
      - Yugoslavia, 1937-1938, undated
    - Foreign policy, 1939-1945, undated, (4 folders)
    - Fourth of July, 1934-1941, undated
    - “F” miscellaneous, 1932-1939
    - Government, 1935-1941, undated, (3 folders)
    - Guild of Saint Barnabas for Nurses, undated
    - “G” miscellaneous, 1936-1941, undated (Box 361)
    - Home ownership, 1931-1937, undated
    - Housing, 1945, undated, (3 folders)
    - “H” miscellaneous, 1937-1944, undated
    - International organizations, 1942-1944, undated, (2 folders)
    - “I-K” miscellaneous, 1936-1945, undated, (3 folders)
    - Labor, 1937-1945, undated, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 362)
    - Lend-lease program, 1941
    - “L” miscellaneous, 1935-1957, undated, (2 folders)
    - Mayoral elections, Cleveland, Ohio, 1935-1941, undated, (4 folders)
    - Memorial Day, 1910-1945, undated, (3 folders)
    - Music, 1936-1940, undated
    - “M” miscellaneous, 1935-1945, undated, (2 folders)
    - National defense, 1933-1941, undated, (5 folders) (Box 363)
    - National Grange, 1939-1943
    - New Deal, 1936-1938
    - North Africa trip, 1945, undated
    - “N-O” miscellaneous, 1937-1944, undated, (2 folders)
    - Patriotism, 1934-1945, undated
    - Political conventions, 1940-1944
    - Presidents, United States
      - Lincoln, Abraham, 1920-1944, undated, (2 folders)
      - McKinley, William, 1878-1945, undated, (3 folders) (Box 364)
      - Miscellany, 1932-1945, undated, (3 folders)
      - Term limits, 1941-1944, undated
    - Public safety, 1934-1940, undated, (3 folders)
    - Public service, 1934-1935, undated
    - “P” miscellaneous, 1937-1958, undated, (4 folders)
    - Race relations, 1934-1935, undated
    - Radio broadcasts, 1937-1943, undated, (2 folders) (Box 365)
    - Recreation, 1936-1939, undated
    - Relief work, 1934-1940, undated, (5 folders)
    - Religion, 1936-1945, undated, (4 folders)
    - Republican party
      - Candidates for office, 1934-1943
      - Miscellany, 1937-1945, undated, (2 folders); (8 folders) (Box 366)
      - National convention, 1944, (2 folders)
    - “Roads to Lasting Peace,” 1943-1945, undated, (3 folders)
    - “R” miscellaneous, 1938-1942, undated
    - Saint Lawrence Seaway project, 1910-1945, undated, (2 folders); (5 folders) (Box 367)
    - Science and industry, 1935-1945, undated, (4 folders)
    - Selective Service System, 1940-1945, undated, (1 folder); (4 folders) (Box 368)
    - Small business, 1941-1944, (2 folders)
    - Snow, Wilbert, 1936
    - Supreme Court, United States
      - Gibbons v. Ogden, 1956
      - McCulloch v. Maryland, 1955, (2 folders)
      - Miscellany, 1930-1953, undated, (3 folders)
      - Taft, William Howard, chief justice, 1948, 1957
    - “S” miscellaneous, 1936-1945, undated, (1 folder) (Box 369)
    - Taxation, 1934-1942, undated, (4 folders)
    - Thanksgiving Day, 1934-1942, undated
    - Traffic safety, 1941-1943
    - Treaty of Greenville (1795), 1935-1945, undated
    - “T” miscellaneous, 1936-1945, undated
    - United Nations, 1943-1945, undated, (4 folders); (10 folders) (Box 370)
    - United Nations Monetary and Financial Conference, Bretton Woods, N.H., 1944-1945, (1 folder) (Box 371)
    - United States News, 1934-1939
    - Unity, 1942-1944, undated
    - “U-V” miscellaneous, 1937-1943, undated, (2 folders)
    - War bonds, 1942-1945
    - Washington, D.C., 1940-1942
    - Women's clubs, 1936-1939, undated
    - World War II
      - Miscellany, 1941-1942, undated, (2 folders)
      - Postwar planning, 1934-1944, undated, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 372)
    - World's Poultry Congress and Exposition, Cleveland, Ohio, 1937-1939 See also Oversize
    - “W” miscellaneous, 1938-1945
    - YMCA, 1931-1944
    - Youth, 1937-1942, undated
- Miscellany, 1896-1964 (Box 372-399)
  Appointment calendars, biographical and family material, newspaper clippings, notes, reports, minutes, printed matter, and scrapbooks.
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material and chronologically therein.
  - Appointment calendars, 1934-1935 (Box 372)
  - Biographical material, 1897, 1924-1958, (2 folders)
  - Bowdoin College, Brunswick, Maine, profile of the school, 1961, (2 folders) (Box 373)
  - Certificates, 1939-1950, undated
  - Drawing and print, 1945-1950
  - Hitz family history and genealogy
    - Hitz, Alex M., 1948-1951
    - Hitz, C. A., 1947-1949
    - Hitz, Ida, 1947-1951, undated
    - Hitz, Nina, 1948-1951
    - Miscellany, 1907-1954, undated
  - Mixed Claims Commission, United States and Germany, 1936-1939, (2 folders)
  - Newspaper clippings
    - 1928-1935
    - 1936-1939, (9 folders) (Box 374)
    - 1940-1942, (9 folders) (Box 375)
    - 1943-1944, (5 folders) (Box 376)
    - 1945, (4 folders); (9 folders) (Box 377)
    - 1946-1947, (8 folders) (Box 378)
    - 1948-1951, (9 folders) (Box 379)
    - 1952, (1 folder) (Box 380)
    - 1953-1955, (6 folders)
    - 1956, (1 folder) (Box 381)
    - 1957, (3 folders)
    - 1958, (4 folders); (3 folders) (Box 382)
    - 1959-1964, (5 folders)
    - Undated, (2 folders); (4 folders) (Box 383)
  - Notes, 1935-1953, undated, (2 folders)
  - Printed matter
    - 1920-1939, (2 folders)
    - 1940-1942, (7 folders) (Box 384)
    - 1943, (2 folders) (Box 385)
    - 1944, (5 folders); (3 folders) (Box 386)
    - 1945, (4 folders); (5 folders) (Box 387)
    - 1946, (2 folders) (Box 388)
    - 1947, (5 folders)
    - 1948, (4 folders) (Box 389)
    - 1949, (3 folders); (1 folder) (Box 390)
    - 1950, (4 folders)
    - 1951, (2 folders) (Box 391)
    - 1952, (3 folders)
    - 1953, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 392)
    - 1954, (4 folders); (2 folders) (Box 393)
    - 1955, (5 folders); (6 folders) (Box 394)
    - 1956, (1 folder); (5 folders) (Box 395)
    - 1957, (2 folders); (3 folders) (Box 396)
    - 1958, (3 folders); (2 folders) (Box 397)
    - 1959-1962, (5 folders)
    - 1963-1964, (3 folders) (Box 398)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Vol. I, 1896-1948, undated, (7 folders)
    - Vol. II, 1927-1954, (4 folders)
    - Vol. III, 1940-1958, undated, (5 folders) (Box 399)
    - Vol. IV, 1925-1963, undated, (3 folders)
    - Vol. V, 1942-1959, undated, (4 folders)
  - Unitarian Service Committee, minutes, 1940
  - Vacation schedules, 1947-1962
- Classified, 1942-1943 (Box CL 1)
  Reports and correspondence.
  Arranged and described according to the series, containers, and folders from which the items were removed.
  - Senate File (Box CL 1)
    - Committees
      - Special Committee Investigating the National Defense Program
        - Alaska and West Coast trip
          - Correspondence and reports, 1942 (Container 51)
        - Middle East trip, 1943, undated (Container 51)
- Oversize, 1927-1952 (Box OV1-OV4)
  Broadsides, maps, photographs, and bound material.
  - Senate file (Box OV 1)
    - Committees
      - Special Committee Investigating the National Defense Program
        - Alaska and West Coast trip
          - Maps
            - 1927-1940 (Container 51)
            - 1941-1947, undated (Container 51) (Box OV 2)
        - Middle East trip, 1941-1943 (Container 51) (Box OV 3)
      - Special Committee to Investigate Gasoline and Fuel Oil Shortages, 1942 (Container 52)
    - Miscellany (Box OV 4)
      - Campaign material, 1940 (Container 53)
  - Supreme Court file
    - Correspondence
      - October term 1945
        - Reder, Jacob and Erna, undated (Container 64)
    - Miscellany
      - Court budget, 1948 (Container 309)
      - United States courts of appeals and state courts, announcement of written opinions, 1952 (Container 325)
  - Speeches and writings
    - Subject file
      - World's Poultry Congress and Exposition, Cleveland, Ohio, 1939 (Container 372)
Appendix: Legal Abbreviations
Administrat [ive, ion] Admin.
Administrat [or, rix] Adm'[r,x]
Agriculture Agric.
America [n] Am.
Associate Assoc.
Association Ass'n
Atlantic Atl.
Authority Auth.
Automobile Auto.
Avenue Ave.
Board Bd.
Brotherhood Bhd.
Brothers Bros.
Building Bldg.
Central Cent.
Chemical Chem.
Commission Comm'n
Commissioner Comm'r
Committee Comm.
Company Co.
Consolidated Consol.
Construction Constr.
Cooperative Coop.
Corporation Corp.
Department Dep't
Development Dev.
Distribut [or, ing] Distrib.
District Dist.
Division Div.
East [ern] E.
Education [al] Educ.
Electric [al, ity] Elec.
Electronic Elec.
Engineer Eng'r
Engineering Eng'g
Enterprise Enter.
Environment Env't
Environmental Envtl.
Equipment Equip.
Exchange Exch.
Execut [or, rix] Ex'[r,x]
Federal Fed.
Federation Fed'n
Financ [e, ial, ing] Fin.
Foundation Found.
General Gen.
Government Gov't
Guaranty Guar.
Hospital Hosp.
Housing Hous.
Incorporate Inc.
Indemnity Indem.
Independent Indep.
Industr [y, ies, ial] Indus.
Institut [e, ion] Inst.
Insurance Ins.
International Int'l
Investment Inv.
Liability Liab.
Limited Ltd.
Litigation Litig.
Machine [ry] Mach.
Manufacturer Mfr.
Manufacturing Mfg.
Market Mkt.
Marketing Mktg.
Metropolitan Metro.
Municipal Mun.
Mutual Mut.
National Nat'l
North [ern] N.
Organiz [ation, ing] Org.
Pacific Pac.
Product [ion] Prod.
Public Pub.
Railroad R.R.
Railway Ry.
Refining Ref.
Road Rd.
Savings Sav.
Securit [y, ies] Sec.
Service Serv.
Society Soc'y
South [ern] S.
Steamship [s] S.S.
Street St.
Surety Sur.
System [s] Sys.
Tele [phone, graph] Tel.
Transport [ation] Transp.
University Univ.
Utility Util.
West [ern] W.